Define Value Opportunities
Welcome back to this session on value creation.
We're now going to zero in on what it takes
to define change opportunities.
And just like before we're going to list those words.
Kinda make them up big here. Defining change opportunities. Let me write that down here.
To define. Change.
And I'll abbreviate this one.
Opportunity. Now, to begin let me define an opportunity.
An opportunity is a set of conditions.
That's a key thought there. It's a set of conditions
that's favorable to an end.
A set of conditions that is favorable to some end. That's an opportunity.
So, now in the language of Six Sigma. I can say
that an opportunity is a function of the first condition
to the Nth condition.
Now, what do I mean by that? Some of you may recall from other sessions,
where I talked about getting a job.
So, you want a job opportunity.
Well, one condition of an opportunity is you gotta be looking.
You gotta have a need for a job.
Another opportunity is that you take the newspaper
to read the potential jobs that are open.
Another condition is that you can read.
See. So, those things have gotta be present for you have a job opportunity. It's that simple.
Now, condition one to condition N. What do we mean of that? Well, that's the first condition.
See, I could just as easily said this, condition one comma, condition two comma,
condition three comma, dot dot dot, condition N.
Through the Nth condition. Where there is a large number of conditions.
Now, we gotta remember this. Hey, this is very important.
Not all these conditions are equally weighted.
Some conditions carry more weight than others,
and that's called the vital few versus the trivial many.
So, what I want to do is go find the vital few conditions that create. Listen to this now.
Keyword I want to go identify.
I want to go define the vital few conditions
that creates change opportunity.
And what change are we talking about? We’re talking about this change.
To go from the is to the ought condition of each,
value need we have, each utility, access, worth need.
So again, I want to define the change opportunity.
That's defining the conditions
that has to change, to create the opportunity,
to close the gaps.
Thereby improving the quality of my life. Thereby bringing greater value into my life.
That's what we’re talking about,
when we say define change opportunity.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.